## Pierre Petillot, Front End Engineer

Paris, France, +33 6 15 97 05 78, petillot.pierre@hotmail.fr

LINKS	GitHub, LinkedIn			
PROFILE	I am a French React.js developer seeking professional opportunities after having studied software development and a one-year working experience on React.js. I am used to React/JavaScript/HTML/CSS good practices, are working as part of a team. I got familiar with the Agile methodology by creating websites for individuals as a freelancer. I am a sociable person, passionate about traveling to uncommon places, I have a taste for explorationand discovering new things, and I am willing to settle down in another country.			
EMPLOYMENT HISTORY				
Nov 2021 — Nov 2022	React developer, Filiatec	h		Paris
	I created a web React application several advanced features: tags, create these features from scrate			
INTERNSHIPS				
Nov 2020 — Feb 2022	Nextcloud 17 and Talend	d developer, Ministè	ère de l'Intérieur	Issy-les-Moulineaux
	My internship was first oriented on creating a Nextcloud 17 plug-in, mostly using PHP. I also created and administrated the Nextcloud server that I had to use to work on this project. I also worked on the management of a Talend platform, this job mostly consisted in orienting the data transiting through the platform.			
EDUCATION				
Oct 2020 — Oct 2022	Front-end Engineer, Openclassroom			Paris
	Front-end development formation specialized in JavaScript and React. I created advanced applications using vanilla JavaScript at first, then React. The projects, being for example managing a bank app user account system or an Airbnb mock-up, can all be seen on my GitHub.			
Sep 2019 — Oct 2020	Devops Engineer, Ecole des technologies numeriques appliquees			
	My first year learning software engineering, during which I was introduced to several technologies and IT jobs. It was after this year I chose to specialize in front-end development.			
SKILLS	HTML & CSS	Expert	JavaScript	Skillful
	Git	Skillful	Redux	Beginner
	React	Skillful	TypeScript	Beginner
EXTRA-CURRICULAR A	CTIVITIES			
Nov 2021 — Present	Website creation, Free-lance			
	I create websites for individuals, using WordPress. Up until now, I have created the following websites: https://ashana-b.com , and https://lagrif.fr , in self-management using the Agile methodology.			
May 2017 — Aug 2019	E-commerce shop managing, free-lance			Paris
	Before learning development, I had an entrepreneurship experience consisting in creating and managing an onli shop of men fashion accessories, using Shopify.			
REFERENCES	Matthieu Rivière from F	iliatech		

REFERENCES Matthieu Rivière from Filiatech

m@leukensis.org  $\cdot$  +33 6 32 22 71 80